<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 13:32:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://thestudentsoutpost.org/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[In the Shades of Fallen Chinar - Screening & Panel Discussion.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>A cultural emergency is being unleashed in the country, from the past few years.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The plot of In the Shade of Fallen Chinar revolves around a group of young artists - students from University of Kashmir. And their tryst with regaining freedom through music, art and resistance. It talks about the factors that inspired their art and how it takes the form of resistance in the strife-torn valley’s innards.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These are bad time for the artists, who try to react to the existing intolerance in the country through their works.
Of the three films denied screening permission at the upcoming International Documentary and Short Film Festival of Kerala, In the Shade of Fallen Chinar, has been on YouTube for several months. Made by Fazil NC and Shawn Sebastian in June 2016, explores the music and visual arts being produced by students of the University. The chinar trees, providing the campus have provided shelter to students exchanging songs, poems, stories, photographs and ideas considered subversive by a government in denial.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>“Conflict is a perfect place for art,” says one of the students. Declares another, “Life is revolution.”</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fazil and Sebastian assemble musicians, photographers and the editor of a campus tabloid – young men and women who have only known conflict, who have been marked by personal loss, and who are deeply affected by the troubles in the Valley. A totemic fallen Chinar tree that has been converted into an art object that helps them express their feelings.
One student neatly sums up the minor efflorescence: “Nothing can happen abruptly. The youth are into escapism…not from reality but the harshness and conflict.”</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the Shade of Fallen Chinar forms a trilogy of campus protest films, along with PN Ramachandra’s The Unbearable Being of Lightness and Kathu Lukose’s March, March, March. The Information and Broadcasting Ministry has denied the International Documentary and Short Film Festival of Kerala permission to screen the three titles.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fazil has travelled to Kashmir several times, and counts many of the university students as his friends. What was initially a set of freewheeling videotaped conversations cohered into a 16-minute tribute to student resistance. The fallen ‘Chinar ka ped’, as they call it has become a metaphorical tale of how choked up the situation in Kashmir is.
Someone like them, in the 90s would’ve picked up a gun; but here they’re picking up the soul with the same ideology - to resist. And art has become an imminent emotional release, to balance your experiences, and not letting accumulate it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The 16-minute film shows Kashmir as it was, before Burhan Muzzafar Wani’s death. Wani, a militant commander of Kashmir’s Hizbul Mujahideen, was killed in an encounter with security forces on July 8, 2016.
Along with the length and breadth of Kashmir that was then afflicted with remorse, University of Kashmir was closed and Mizraab, the college journal, was discontinued after two editions in June chapter.
Mizraab means a plectrum device that strikes the strings of a musical instrument known as Rabaab. And just like how a plectrum is used to stir notes of music, the fortnightly was started with the aim to stir the young, creative minds of Kashmir. The aim was to not depend on the dilapitated state’s constrained press, but to have a space that allowed them the fundamental right to ‘freedom of speech and expression.’
Brought together by the language of art, literature and music they use to communicate their resistance, these students gathered to conspire a riot — not one of violence the Valley was otherwise used to, but a more riveting one — that of their powerful voices, beautifully woven words, soulful music and vivid art.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Sebastian, one of the directors of the film, says most of the students they met during the making of the film spoke of art as an avenue to vent their accumulated anger of several years. “While a section of the youth expresses through stone pelting, another section uses art to show their resistance. This film is about them,” he says.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For Qazi Khytul Abyad, a 23-year-old fine arts student, gathering around the chinar was not planned. So as to not let the place seem abandoned, Abyad and other students from the nearby Faculty of Visual and Performing Arts were among the first who started gathering around the tree. Other students in the University followed suit. “Artistes gathered around the tree to sing, write and draw, and get to know each other,” she says.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Art is a universal language for everyone — irrespective of religion, language, race and nationality. Put together by their poignant hurt and love for art, gather near the Chinar — giving them hope, that maybe, their amalgamation could bring in a change that decades of uprisings have failed to.
The students’ dissent is probably not as striking as that of the ones resorting to violence. Theirs is probably just an informal, disorderly set, and from what it seems, their outbursts, their sketches or the lyrics of their songs may not be as obvious as the pellet guns or stones the others wield, but in the countless pages of history that the unrests in Kashmir has seen, theirs might make for the more vivid ones.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On similar terms, though the ranges vary - Bangalore has been facing a similar crisis, day in; day out. And, The Students’ Outpost, aims to form a faction of students’ who believe that students should emerge through the forefront, establishing concrete terms against the political situation of the country.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An open platform that will welcome thinkers, fighter and dreamers of all sorts, as we forge new solidarities, and engage critically, delving into essential dialogue, of our days. Only continual self-reflection - about our positions and fundamental freedoms, will provide us with tools to resist the system we’re complicit in.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Hence, this event. A film screening, to involve under interest, to dialogue and discourse. Through, the aide of a film screening, and a panel discussion, that drives into, to add effect to a discussion of change.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Kerala High Court on Friday, 16 June 2017, dismissed a petition by Shawn Sebastian, one of the directors of In The Shade of Fallen Chinar, against the I&amp;B ministry&#8217;s decision to withhold screening permission for the film (along with another couple of documentaries) at the 10th International Documentary and Short Film Festival, in the capital city of Kerala - Trivandrum.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/17/fallen-chinar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/17/fallen-chinar.html</guid><category><![CDATA[In_the_Shades_of_Fallen_Chinar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Event]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bangalore]]></category><category><![CDATA[Screening]]></category><category><![CDATA[Panel_Discussion]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[In the Shades of Fallen Chinar - Screening & Panel Discussion.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>A cultural emergency is being unleashed in the country, from the past few years.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The plot of In the Shade of Fallen Chinar revolves around a group of young artists - students from University of Kashmir. And their tryst with regaining freedom through music, art and resistance. It talks about the factors that inspired their art and how it takes the form of resistance in the strife-torn valley’s innards.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These are bad time for the artists, who try to react to the existing intolerance in the country through their works.
Of the three films denied screening permission at the upcoming International Documentary and Short Film Festival of Kerala, In the Shade of Fallen Chinar, has been on YouTube for several months. Made by Fazil NC and Shawn Sebastian in June 2016, explores the music and visual arts being produced by students of the University. The chinar trees, providing the campus have provided shelter to students exchanging songs, poems, stories, photographs and ideas considered subversive by a government in denial.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>“Conflict is a perfect place for art,” says one of the students. Declares another, “Life is revolution.”</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fazil and Sebastian assemble musicians, photographers and the editor of a campus tabloid – young men and women who have only known conflict, who have been marked by personal loss, and who are deeply affected by the troubles in the Valley. A totemic fallen Chinar tree that has been converted into an art object that helps them express their feelings.
One student neatly sums up the minor efflorescence: “Nothing can happen abruptly. The youth are into escapism…not from reality but the harshness and conflict.”</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the Shade of Fallen Chinar forms a trilogy of campus protest films, along with PN Ramachandra’s The Unbearable Being of Lightness and Kathu Lukose’s March, March, March. The Information and Broadcasting Ministry has denied the International Documentary and Short Film Festival of Kerala permission to screen the three titles.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fazil has travelled to Kashmir several times, and counts many of the university students as his friends. What was initially a set of freewheeling videotaped conversations cohered into a 16-minute tribute to student resistance. The fallen ‘Chinar ka ped’, as they call it has become a metaphorical tale of how choked up the situation in Kashmir is.
Someone like them, in the 90s would’ve picked up a gun; but here they’re picking up the soul with the same ideology - to resist. And art has become an imminent emotional release, to balance your experiences, and not letting accumulate it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The 16-minute film shows Kashmir as it was, before Burhan Muzzafar Wani’s death. Wani, a militant commander of Kashmir’s Hizbul Mujahideen, was killed in an encounter with security forces on July 8, 2016.
Along with the length and breadth of Kashmir that was then afflicted with remorse, University of Kashmir was closed and Mizraab, the college journal, was discontinued after two editions in June chapter.
Mizraab means a plectrum device that strikes the strings of a musical instrument known as Rabaab. And just like how a plectrum is used to stir notes of music, the fortnightly was started with the aim to stir the young, creative minds of Kashmir. The aim was to not depend on the dilapitated state’s constrained press, but to have a space that allowed them the fundamental right to ‘freedom of speech and expression.’
Brought together by the language of art, literature and music they use to communicate their resistance, these students gathered to conspire a riot — not one of violence the Valley was otherwise used to, but a more riveting one — that of their powerful voices, beautifully woven words, soulful music and vivid art.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Sebastian, one of the directors of the film, says most of the students they met during the making of the film spoke of art as an avenue to vent their accumulated anger of several years. “While a section of the youth expresses through stone pelting, another section uses art to show their resistance. This film is about them,” he says.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For Qazi Khytul Abyad, a 23-year-old fine arts student, gathering around the chinar was not planned. So as to not let the place seem abandoned, Abyad and other students from the nearby Faculty of Visual and Performing Arts were among the first who started gathering around the tree. Other students in the University followed suit. “Artistes gathered around the tree to sing, write and draw, and get to know each other,” she says.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Art is a universal language for everyone — irrespective of religion, language, race and nationality. Put together by their poignant hurt and love for art, gather near the Chinar — giving them hope, that maybe, their amalgamation could bring in a change that decades of uprisings have failed to.
The students’ dissent is probably not as striking as that of the ones resorting to violence. Theirs is probably just an informal, disorderly set, and from what it seems, their outbursts, their sketches or the lyrics of their songs may not be as obvious as the pellet guns or stones the others wield, but in the countless pages of history that the unrests in Kashmir has seen, theirs might make for the more vivid ones.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On similar terms, though the ranges vary - Bangalore has been facing a similar crisis, day in; day out. And, The Students’ Outpost, aims to form a faction of students’ who believe that students should emerge through the forefront, establishing concrete terms against the political situation of the country.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An open platform that will welcome thinkers, fighter and dreamers of all sorts, as we forge new solidarities, and engage critically, delving into essential dialogue, of our days. Only continual self-reflection - about our positions and fundamental freedoms, will provide us with tools to resist the system we’re complicit in.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Hence, this event. A film screening, to involve under interest, to dialogue and discourse. Through, the aide of a film screening, and a panel discussion, that drives into, to add effect to a discussion of change.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Kerala High Court on Friday, 16 June 2017, dismissed a petition by Shawn Sebastian, one of the directors of In The Shade of Fallen Chinar, against the I&amp;B ministry&#8217;s decision to withhold screening permission for the film (along with another couple of documentaries) at the 10th International Documentary and Short Film Festival, in the capital city of Kerala - Trivandrum.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/17/fallen-chinar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/17/fallen-chinar.html</guid><category><![CDATA[In_the_Shades_of_Fallen_Chinar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Event]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bangalore]]></category><category><![CDATA[Screening]]></category><category><![CDATA[Panel_Discussion]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why We Must Organize]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Varkey Parakkal, student and member, TSO, on why we need to organize.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A considerable part of my first year in Bangalore was spent trying to overcome culture shock, as a student and as an activist. Eventually, it dawned on me that there were two worlds within this city and that they were pliable citizens of the state for two completely opposite reasons. There are the middle/upper-middle classes, these are your average IT guys, engineers, college students and so on, most of them migrants and immigrants. They mostly come from favorable caste-backgrounds as well. The news makes them uncomfortable, but not so uncomfortable (yet) as to take organized political action. Coming to the streets in protest is seen as a sort of mild-taboo/inconvenience. Occasionally when conscience raises it&#8217;s head in the form of guilt, they tell themselves the age old apolitical mantra "All politics is bad. It&#8217;s better to stay out of all this." and that makes everything alright again. Occasional candle light assemblies in front of Town Hall is acceptable, even encouraged, but workers/students unions and strikes are a big no-no.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the other end of the spectrum lie the bottom-half of the working class, the wage laborers and the unemployed. They too have a fair share of 'immigrants', but immigrants of a different kind. An example of this would be the Powrakarmikas/sanitation workers of Bangalore, mostly comprising of women from the Madiga caste who&#8217;ve migrated from Andhra Pradesh. They are far more organized and politically charged compared to the middle and upper middle classes, but this is mostly out of sheer necessity that is caused by their socio-economic conditions. For them every day, every moment is a fight against systematized oppression. But the mechanisms of oppression paired up with the passive ignorance of the middle classes makes any form of protest extremely difficult. This often means that pressure within the system builds up and this head of steam bursts when uncontrollable discontent becomes chaos and violence. The garment workers riots in Bangalore is a recent example of this. The docile and apolitical nature of Bangalore&#8217;s populace, especially that of the students lets these socio-economic inequalities fester.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This condition of selective blindness and forced compliance has made Bangalore into a breeding ground of predatory capitalism and well-oiled mechanisms of oppression. This means that large IT companies can lay off and underpay thousands of employees with minimal resistance. This also means that the Bangalore Municipality can employ thousands of workers using illegal contract systems and pay them criminally low wages and expect minimal retaliation. Major educational institutions against which multiple cases allegations of sexual violations exist can function comfortably knowing full well that their students won’t put up a fight. Right-wing fundamentalists can shoot dissidents in the head and get away with it. The list is long.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I came to Bangalore almost two years ago the Sangh forces were only beginning to flex their muscles at a national level. A fair share of my student life in Bangalore so far is riddled with vain attempts to organize its students in some form. But I feel that these failures on my part have in many ways helped me understand some gaping holes in the tactics that I’ve used in the past to bring students together. More and more I’m starting to meet students who wish to do something against “all that’s happening” but are not sure how to. There are also students who hide their discontent and will to react because they are overwhelmed and intimidated by the nature of their institute’s management. It’s easy to understand why. The last thing anyone who has access to near unlimited amounts of power would want, be it the college management or the central government, is for the people under them to organize. Because of this reason organizing within an educational institution in Bangalore is a near impossible task. And two years of failed attempts have led me to believe that the only logical conclusion is for us students to organize outside of our management. This need not be a union in the traditional sense, but a collective of students from all the colleges in Bangalore coming together to create a platform for discussion and action. We must do this is because we’re up against very organized oppressors, from the right-wing forces that have taken hold of the government to the college managements, and within this system there is very little we can do as individuals. I feel that time is ripe for such an initiative; for students to politicize and organize across campuses in the city.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/15/why-we-must-organize.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/15/why-we-must-organize.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Students_Union]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bangalore]]></category><category><![CDATA[TSO]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why We Must Organize]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Varkey Parakkal, student and member, TSO, on why we need to organize.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A considerable part of my first year in Bangalore was spent trying to overcome culture shock, as a student and as an activist. Eventually, it dawned on me that there were two worlds within this city and that they were pliable citizens of the state for two completely opposite reasons. There are the middle/upper-middle classes, these are your average IT guys, engineers, college students and so on, most of them migrants and immigrants. They mostly come from favorable caste-backgrounds as well. The news makes them uncomfortable, but not so uncomfortable (yet) as to take organized political action. Coming to the streets in protest is seen as a sort of mild-taboo/inconvenience. Occasionally when conscience raises it&#8217;s head in the form of guilt, they tell themselves the age old apolitical mantra "All politics is bad. It&#8217;s better to stay out of all this." and that makes everything alright again. Occasional candle light assemblies in front of Town Hall is acceptable, even encouraged, but workers/students unions and strikes are a big no-no.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On the other end of the spectrum lie the bottom-half of the working class, the wage laborers and the unemployed. They too have a fair share of 'immigrants', but immigrants of a different kind. An example of this would be the Powrakarmikas/sanitation workers of Bangalore, mostly comprising of women from the Madiga caste who&#8217;ve migrated from Andhra Pradesh. They are far more organized and politically charged compared to the middle and upper middle classes, but this is mostly out of sheer necessity that is caused by their socio-economic conditions. For them every day, every moment is a fight against systematized oppression. But the mechanisms of oppression paired up with the passive ignorance of the middle classes makes any form of protest extremely difficult. This often means that pressure within the system builds up and this head of steam bursts when uncontrollable discontent becomes chaos and violence. The garment workers riots in Bangalore is a recent example of this. The docile and apolitical nature of Bangalore&#8217;s populace, especially that of the students lets these socio-economic inequalities fester.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This condition of selective blindness and forced compliance has made Bangalore into a breeding ground of predatory capitalism and well-oiled mechanisms of oppression. This means that large IT companies can lay off and underpay thousands of employees with minimal resistance. This also means that the Bangalore Municipality can employ thousands of workers using illegal contract systems and pay them criminally low wages and expect minimal retaliation. Major educational institutions against which multiple cases allegations of sexual violations exist can function comfortably knowing full well that their students won’t put up a fight. Right-wing fundamentalists can shoot dissidents in the head and get away with it. The list is long.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I came to Bangalore almost two years ago the Sangh forces were only beginning to flex their muscles at a national level. A fair share of my student life in Bangalore so far is riddled with vain attempts to organize its students in some form. But I feel that these failures on my part have in many ways helped me understand some gaping holes in the tactics that I’ve used in the past to bring students together. More and more I’m starting to meet students who wish to do something against “all that’s happening” but are not sure how to. There are also students who hide their discontent and will to react because they are overwhelmed and intimidated by the nature of their institute’s management. It’s easy to understand why. The last thing anyone who has access to near unlimited amounts of power would want, be it the college management or the central government, is for the people under them to organize. Because of this reason organizing within an educational institution in Bangalore is a near impossible task. And two years of failed attempts have led me to believe that the only logical conclusion is for us students to organize outside of our management. This need not be a union in the traditional sense, but a collective of students from all the colleges in Bangalore coming together to create a platform for discussion and action. We must do this is because we’re up against very organized oppressors, from the right-wing forces that have taken hold of the government to the college managements, and within this system there is very little we can do as individuals. I feel that time is ripe for such an initiative; for students to politicize and organize across campuses in the city.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/15/why-we-must-organize.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/15/why-we-must-organize.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Students_Union]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bangalore]]></category><category><![CDATA[TSO]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost - About]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>TSO is a group of young people who believe that students should be at the forefront of the emerging nation-wide resistance to Brahminism and fascism. Campuses across the country are in ferment, and it is vital that students politicize and organize to speak truth to power and resist the systematic saffronisation of higher education. We aim to be an open platform that will welcome thinkers, fighters and dreamers of all kinds, as we forge new solidarities and engage critically with questions of our day. The organization shall strive to unite students from across Bangalore in a collective effort that can channel our energies into political action, and in Ambedkar’s words, Educate, Agitate and Organize. Eschewing traditional forms of political organizing, we are in favour of an open, democratic space with no hierarchy (strongly in favour) or institutional affiliation. Only continual self-reflection; about our positions and our privileges will give us the tools to resist the profoundly unjust system we are complicit in.
TSO is born out of the hope that this an ideal that inspires more young people, and that when we come together, it can be the beginning of something truly radical, subversive and fearless.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/11/the-students-outpost-about3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/11/the-students-outpost-about3.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Students]]></category><category><![CDATA[Outpost]]></category><category><![CDATA[Union]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost - About]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>TSO is a group of young people who believe that students should be at the forefront of the emerging nation-wide resistance to Brahminism and fascism. Campuses across the country are in ferment, and it is vital that students politicize and organize to speak truth to power and resist the systematic saffronisation of higher education. We aim to be an open platform that will welcome thinkers, fighters and dreamers of all kinds, as we forge new solidarities and engage critically with questions of our day. The organization shall strive to unite students from across Bangalore in a collective effort that can channel our energies into political action, and in Ambedkar’s words, Educate, Agitate and Organize. Eschewing traditional forms of political organizing, we are in favour of an open, democratic space with no hierarchy (strongly in favour) or institutional affiliation. Only continual self-reflection; about our positions and our privileges will give us the tools to resist the profoundly unjust system we are complicit in.
TSO is born out of the hope that this an ideal that inspires more young people, and that when we come together, it can be the beginning of something truly radical, subversive and fearless.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/11/the-students-outpost-about3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://thestudentsoutpost.org/2017/07/11/the-students-outpost-about3.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Students]]></category><category><![CDATA[Outpost]]></category><category><![CDATA[Union]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Students' Outpost]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>